# Lee Macaulay

### **Broadcast Journalist**

Broadcast and multimedia journalist with 2+ years experience working in professional newsrooms at both the BBC and in commercial radio stations. Originally from Kendal, Cumbria, I've worked as a journalist across the North East, Cumbria and Lancashire.

#### **SKILLS**

#### Radio Reporter

Advanced

field recording | adobe audition |

quick edit pro

## **Digital Production**

Advanced

tweetdeck | mobile video shooting | splice ios | png | bbc cps and vivo

### **Radio Broadcaster**

Intermediate

live reporting | news reading | desk driving | radioman

#### **Web and Computer**

Advanced

html/css | linux/ubuntu | wordpress | server admin

#### **Radio Producer**

Intermediate

enps | subediting |

reporter deployments | newsgathering |

creative treatments

#### Miscellaneous

Master

full clean uk driving license | bbc mandatory training

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Broadcast Journalist (Newsroom) at BBC Radio Cumbria

September 2015 - Current

http://www.bbc.co.uk/radiocumbria

Reporter, producer and newsreader on the BBC's local radio station for Cumbria which reaches around one in three adults a week.

- Produced Mike Zeller at Breakfast outside broadcast from Grasmere for the reopening of the A591 following damage from Storm Desmond.
- Reported for BBC Radio 4, BBC Radio Wales and BBC Tees during the 2015 Cumbrian floods.
- Regularly read bulletins, produce breakfast programmes, report live and write for news blog BBC Cumbria Live.
- Produced two separate week-long programme strands.

## Multimedia News and Sport Reporter at CFM Radio

**October 2014 - August 2015** 

http://www.cfmradio.co.uk

Gathered audio and wrote copy for hourly bulletins on Bauer Radio's commercial radio station broadcasting to North and West Cumbria. Updated social media and wrote news articles for the web.

- Reported from the Morecambe Bay inquiry report event for the Bauer City Network
- Reported from the 2015 General Election for the Bauer City Network

## Freelance Multimedia Reporter at Metro Radio and TFM

July 2014 - September 2014

http://www.metroradio.co.uk

Gathered audio and wrote copy for hourly bulletins on Bauer Radio's commercial radio stations for the North East. Updated social media and wrote news articles for the web.

## Freelance Multimedia Reporter at Rock FM

May 2014 - June 2014

http://www.rockfm.co.uk

### Work Experience at ITV Border

May 2014 - May 2014

http://www.itv.co.uk/border

- Produced and edited a package for weekend bulletins
- Wrote and cut video for breakfast bulletins

### Radio Festival Radio at The Radio Academy

October 2013 - October 2013

https://www.radioacademy.org/

Worked with a team of young broadcasters to make radio from, and about, the UK radio industry's biggest event. Edited, co-produced and co-presented daily podcasts and produced a package about future user interfaces in radio.

#### Casual Broadcast Assistant at BBC Radio Cumbria

April 2013 - June 2014

http://www.bbc.co.uk/radiocumbria

Provided on-air production and phone support for weekend and weekday programmes.

#### **EDUCATION**

# PGDip Broadcast Journalism at University of Central Lancashire

2013 - 2014

Major courses: digital journalism | media law | public affairs

# BA (Hons) Journalism, Film and Media at Cardiff University

2006 - 2009

## GCSEs & A Levels Various Subjects at Kirkbie Kendal School

1999 - 2006

Major courses: a level sociology | a level business studies | a level religious studies (philosophy & ethics) | 10.5 gcses (a\*-c)

#### **AWARDS**

# **Bronze, Best Journalistic Programming** at Student Radio Awards 2007

as part of the Xpress Radio News Team

# **Best Mainstream Show** at Cardiff Student Media Awards 2007

# Best News Reporter at Cardiff Student Media Awards 2007

judged by Jon Snow, Channel 4 News

#### **INTERESTS**

reading walking technology

non-fiction | margaret atwood | bryan-lee o'malley

novice hillwalker | one wainwright summit

pebble smartwatch | ios | xbox one